kinto behr

data scientist

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a data scientist and statistician with expertise in R and a keen interest in process automation, package development, and applied statistics. Although I am most comfortable in R, I have varying degrees of experience with a number of other languages from SQL (fluent), through Python, HTML/CSS and JavaScript (intermediate), to C++ (beginner).

Outside of work, I am an active contributor to the open source software community, having developed or made large contributions to a number of R packages. More information and an expanded resume are available at https://kinto-b.github.io

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Statistician

Social Research Centre | 2022 - Present

I am currently situated in the statistical methods team, working on automating our survey weighting procedure for the Life in Australia study.

Data Scientist

Social Research Centre | 2020 - 2022

I was the lead data scientist on the SES, which approaches hundreds of thousands of higher education students each year. In this capacity, I was responsible for maintaining the data infrustructure throughout the full length of the pipeline from sample collection and validation through fieldwork operations and data processing, to report production.

In addition, I made key contributions to the in-house R package architecture and Shiny application suite. In particular, I

- Authored and/or maintained the majority of in-house packages
- Trained other data scientists in R package development, helping them to become maintainers in their own right

• Developed a number of complex Shiny applications which became core to projects across the business, including one which won a company-wide competition

EDUCATION

Master of Statistics

University of New South Wales | 2021 - Present

• Maintaining a 4.0 GPA with a current rounded average of 90

Bachelor of Arts (Honours)

University of Melbourne | 2021 - Present

- Graduated top of my class with a GPA of 4.0 and a rounded average of 87%. (Transcript available upon request).
- Wrote a thesis in philosophy on the theory of knowledge.

Bachelor of Arts and Bachelor of Science

Monash University | 2013 - 2017

- Achieved a GPA of 3.93 with a rounded average of 87%. (Transcript available upon request).
- Majored in physics and philosophy; minored in mathematics and Japanese language.
- Received numerous academic awards including the Dean's List Fellowship Award and five best in unit awards (for achieving top marks across various physics classes).

SELECTED HONOURS

- 2019 Hastie Prize in Philosophy, the University of Melbourne
- 2016 Peter J. Lloyd Prize in Theoretical Physics, Monash University